A Guide to the John Davidson Ewing Marriage Licenses, 1841-1858
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
John Davidson Ewing Marriage Licenses, 1841-1858
Library of Virginia
21111
20 leaves
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Henry Thompson Louthan, Duane, Virginia, 7 August 2004.
Biographical Information
John Davidson Ewing was born in either 1787 or 1788 in Rockingham County, Virginia. He attended Washington Academy (Washington and Lee University) from 1806 to 1807, and Hampden-Sidney College from 1807 to 1809 and he received an A.B. He graduated from the Union Theological Seminary (Virginia) in 1810. He taught school in Lexington, Virginia, from 1810 to 1813. Ewing was ordained 2 October 1813 and his first congregations were Lebanon and Windy Cove churches in Rockbridge County, Virginia, from 1813 to 1821. Ewing then served Falling Spring Church in Rockbridge County from 1822 to 1854, and lastly Fancy Hill Church from 1854 to 1877. Ewing married Drusilla Tate (ca. 1784-1859), and they had children. Ewing died 11 January 1877 in Rockbridge County.
Scope and Content
Marriage licenses, 1841-1858, from Rockbridge County, Virginia. The marriages were performed by Reverend John Ewing, pastor of Falling Spring Presbyterian Church. Also includes a letter from Henry Thompson Louthan (1866-1953) concerning the provenance of the records, as well as a typescript list of the marriages and where they are recorded in the Rockbridge County court records.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically
Contents List
- Marriage license, 13 January 1841, for Joel Baldock and Susan Elizabeth Penn., 1 leaf.
- Marriage license, 5 June 1846, for Charles B. McClung and Mary Jane Moffett., 1 leaf.
- Marriage license, 16 February 1847, for John G. Hamilton and Hannah Frances Grigsby., 1 leaf.
- Marriage license, 18 April 1854, for Philip Fout and Harriet Mayo., 1 leaf.
- Marriage license, 21 July 1854, for William Smith and Mary E. Harrison., 1 leaf.
- Marriage license, 16 September 1854, for James Brooks and Nancy Jane Rowlison., 1 leaf.
- Marriage license, 17 October 1854, for Gabriel S. Fisher and Tabitha W. Smith., 1 leaf.
- Marriage license, 25 December 1854, for William Watkins and Frances Tolley., 1 leaf.
- Marriage license, 30 May 1855, for Joseph G. Steele and Isabel P. Sterrett., 1 leaf.
- Marriage license, 24 December 1855, for Thomas Jefferson Austin and Mary Frances Mayes., 1 leaf.
- Marriage license, 24 November 1856, for Samuel Smith and Nancy Jane Newcomer., 1 leaf.
- Marriage license, 3 December 1856, for Robert W. Wallace and Lumina Luster., 1 leaf.
- Marriage license, 31 December 1856, for William P. Jones and Ann S. Swinney., 1 leaf.
- Marriage license, 23 March 1857, for Robert Welch and Susan A. Newcomer., 1 leaf.
- Marriage license, 19 June 1857, for James M. Fitch and Jane T. Braford., 1 leaf.
- Marriage license, 3 May 1858, for George Shafer and Frances P. Wilcher., 1 leaf.
- Marriage license, 25 May 1858, for Willoughby M. Harris and Ellen C. Schindel., 1 leaf.
- Marriage license, 2 August 1858, for David M. Wilcher and Sarah E. Sackey., 1 leaf.
- Letter, 7 August 1936, from Henry T. Louthan, Duane, Virginia, to Morgan P. Robinson of the Virginia State Library, Richmond, Virginia, concerning the marriage licenses and their provenance. Letter is a copy., 1 leaf.
- Note, n.d., specifying where the marriages are located in the Rockbridge County Register of Marriages on microfilm at the Library of Virginia., 1 leaf.